Guide to the Douglas Bennet Papers, 1940 - 2004
Douglas Bennet Papers,1940 - 2004
- Series III: Roosevelt Center for American Policy Studies,1981-1983
  - Resignation and departure
    - Pre-resignation fight, 1983 June 17-27 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Resignation, etc., 1983 February-June (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Notes about resignation, 1983 June-September (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Successor to Roosevelt Center, 1983 June-October (Box 63, Folder 9-11)
- Series IV: National Public Radio,1983-1993
  - Subject files
    - AID correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 64, Folder 1-4)
    - Annual reports, 1982-1991 (Box 64, Folder 5-6)
    - Articles and speeches, 1978-1988 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Audiotape: National Public Radio, Retrospective on the Gulf: The Questions of War, 1991 January (Box 91 [oversize])
    - Audiotape: Dale K. Ouzts, Prima roast, Branson, MO, 1987 September 13 (Box 92 [oversize])
    - Audiotapes: Conan Teleconference, 1991 March 7-8 (Box 92 [oversize])
    - Audiotape: Illegal Abortion, I and II, 1992 April 21-22 (Box 92 [oversize])
    - Audiotape: The Pennekamp Rap!, 1993 January 29 (Box 92 [oversize])
    - Audiotape: Doug Bennet - Prima Tributes, 1993 April 27 (Box 92 [oversize])
    - Audiotape: Douglas J. Bennet, President National Public Radio,Public Radio: A Signal of Distinction, undated (Box 92 [oversize])
    - Big black notebook
      - Companywide objectives, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 8)
      - CEO objectives, 1984-1989 (Box 64, Folder 9-10)
      - Multiple tabs, 1984-1989 (Box 65, Folder 1-2)
      - Loose materials, 1988-1992 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Clippings archive, 1982-1985 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 1982-1993 (Box 88 [oversize], Folder 6)
    - Departure, correspondence, 1993 March-April (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Departure, 1993 March-May (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Departure, farewell event, 1993 April 7 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Employment, 1986-1992 (Box 65, Folder 8-10)
    - Fanfare campaign, 1986 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Executive compensation, 1991 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Foreign policy pamphlets, 1992 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Loose materials, ca. 1992 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Memoranda, 1984-1985 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - NPR, 1983-1993 (Box 66, Folder 6-9)
    - Phone lists, 1992-1993 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Photos (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Press, 1983-1993 (Box 67, Folder 2-3)
    - Retreat, 1989 October 2: NPR 1983-1989 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Retreat, 1989 October 2: duplicate materials (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Retreat, 1989 October 2: confidential, 1989-1993 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - State of public radio programming in FY 1984, 1983 December (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Transition, 1989, 1993 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Transition - Joe Dembo, 1993 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Transition - Joe Dembo, 1993 (Box 68, Folder 1-3)
    - Videotape: Douglas Bennet: Edward R. Murrow Award, Corporation for Public Broadcasting, 1993 May (Box 91 [oversize])
    - WRI - partnership for sustainable development, 1991 December 3 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - WRI - visions of a sustainable world, 1992 June 26 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Speeches and articles
    - Oversight and investigations subcommittee, 1984 February 10 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Communications subcommittee, 1984 February 22 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Labor, HHS and education subcommittee, 1984 March 26 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Commerce, science and transportation, 1984 March 26 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - PRC, 1984 April 9 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Commerce, justice, state and the judiciary subcommittee, 1984 May 3 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - PTFMA, 1984 May 19 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - SECA, 1984 October 13 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - National women's democratic club, 1984 October 29 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - CFR - international ethics and campaign politics, 1984 October 30 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - Commonwealth Club, San Francisco, 1984 November 8-9 (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Speeches, 1984 May-November (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - NYU conference, 1985 March 1-2 (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Washington - higher education speech, 1985 March 5 (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - Speeches, 1985 March-July (Box 68, Folder 20)
    - Chautauqua institution, 1985 August 21 (Box 69, Folder 1-2)
    - Pine article, 1986 February (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Foreign relations testimony, 1986 April 21 (Box 69, Folder 4-5)
    - PTFMA, 1986 May 28 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Pittsburgh State University appreciation dinner, 1986 November 12 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Society of professional journalists, Atlanta, 1986 November 13 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Speeches, 1986 October-November (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - PRC, San Diego, 1986 (Box 69, Folder 10-11)
    - President's report, 1987 May 2 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - EBU, Torremolinos, Spain, 1987 May 9-13 (Box 69, Folder 13-14)
    - Media and philanthropy, Chicago Tribune, 1987 June 2 (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Speeches, 1987 August-November (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Speeches, 1988 April-May (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - PRC, 1988 May 21 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Program corporation of America, Syracuse, NY, 1988 September 15-16 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Benton fellowship: notes, 1989 March 9 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - EPR, 1989 September (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Cleveland city club, 1989 December 20 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Speeches, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - University of Missouri commencement, 1991 January 6 (Box 70, Folder 9-10)
    - Ohio State University, communications class, 1991 March 12 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Nieman fellows, Boston, MA, 1991 March 13 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Mass communications conference, Jackson, MS, 1991 March 20-22 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Carnegie corporation, 1991 April 25 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - The planning forum, Toronto, Canada, 1991 April 29-30 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Council on Foreign Relations committee meeting, 1991 May 23 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Speeches, 1991 September-November and undated (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - European Broadcasters Union, 1992 April 14 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Rebuilding to Become a Leader, 1992 April (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - City club of Seattle, 1992 May 7 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Dowling College, Oakdale, NY, 1992 May 9 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - PTFMA conference, Ft. Meyers, FL, 1992 May 27-28 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - NAB/radio conference, Montreux, Switzerland, 1992 June 10-13 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Wesleyan seminar, 1992 November 12 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - du Pont forum, Columbia University, 1993 January 28 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Speeches, 1993 January-February (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Speeches, notes, undated (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Speeches - subject files
      - Campus free speech, 1989 (Box 71, Folder 11)
      - Commercial speech/federal funding (Box 71, Folder 12)
      - First ammendment, 1990-1991 (Box 71, Folder 13)
      - Flag burning (Box 71, Folder 14)
      - Foreign policy speech file (Box 71, Folder 15)
      - Jackson/art (Box 71, Folder 16)
      - Media issues, fairness, indecency (Box 71, Folder 17)
      - NEA funding issue/Corcoran/artist's space, 1989 (Box 71, Folder 18)
      - Public radio speech material (Box 71, Folder 19)
      - Statistics, 1990-1991 (Box 71, Folder 20-22)
- Series V: Personal,1940-2004
  - Correspondence
    - Chronological
      - 1972 May-1976 December (Box 72, Folder 1-11)
      - 1984-1986 (Box 72, Folder 12)
      - 1987-1993 and undated (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - 1994-1999 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - 2002-2004 and undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Alphabetical
      - Bowles, Chester, 1960, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 4)
      - Connecticut, 1974-1975 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      - Family letters from Europe, 1962 March-April (Box 73, Folder 6)
      - Family Christmas cards, 1940-1972 and undated (Box 73, Folder 7)
      - India
        - Halina and John, 1963-1964 (Box 73, Folder 8)
        - Letters from friends, 1963-1965 (Box 73, Folder 9)
        - Lyme letters, 1963-1965 and undated (Box 73, Folder 10-13)
        - Phoebe and Jim, 1963-1965 (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - Education
    - Wesleyan, 1955-1959
      - 1955-1957 (Box 74, Folder 1-13)
      - 1956-1959 (Box 75, Folder 1-15)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 76, Folder 1-4)
      - Honors thesis, 1959 May (Box 76, Folder 5)
      - Photos, Alpha Chi Rho, 1957-1958 (Box 93 [oversize], Folder 6)
      - EQV: a history, 1962, 1969 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Berkeley, 1959-60
      - 1959-1960 (Box 76, Folder 7-10)
      - 1959-1960 (Box 77, Folder 1-7)
    - Harvard, 1960-1967
      - 1960-1961 (Box 77, Folder 8-14)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 78, Folder 1-17)
      - 1961-1963 (Box 79, Folder 1-5)
      - Dissertation
        - 1962-1966 and undated (Box 79, Folder 6-13)
        - 1966-1967 and undated (Box 80, Folder 1-14)
        - 1967 May and undated (Box 81, Folder 1-6)
        - Sources and bibliography (Box 94 [oversize])
  - Subject files
    - Address book, ca. 1969 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Artwork, youthful (Box 93 {oversize], Folder 8)
    - Beauvoir school, 1972-1974 (Box 81, Folder 8-13)
    - Beauvoir school, 1975-1976 (Box 82, Folder 1-4)
    - Car park, 1990 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Center for the study of democratic institutions, 1973-1974 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Connecticut - future jobs, 1972-1973 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Connecticut house, 1984-1991 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Cosmos Club, 1989-1993 (Box 82, Folder 9-10)
    - Date books, 1973-1974 (Box 82, Folder 11-12)
    - Date books, 1974-1977 (Box 83, Folder 1-6)
    - Date books, 1978-1982, 1993-94 (Box 84, Folder 1-8)
    - Frelek, Ryszard, 1990-1991 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - High school yearbook, 1955 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Insurance, 1989-1992 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Loose materials (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Music, clarinet (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Music, Lessons in harmony, 1931 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Personal, 1987 and undated (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Photos, family (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Scouting sash (Box 93 [oversize], Folder 7)
    - Scrap book, 1844-1942 (Box 93 [oversize], Folder 9)
    - Speeches, 1994, 2008 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Taxes, 1985-1991 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Thapa, 1986-1992 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Vacation, 1986 and undated (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Vacation, South Bar, 1990 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Wesleyan, 1972-1975, 1991 (Box 86, Folder 3-4)
    - Where are they now? lists, 1983-1992 and undated (Box 86, Folder 5)
- Series V: News Clips,1993-1995
  - 1993 March 4-September 7 (Box 95, Folder 1-7)
  - 1993 September 9-30 (Box 96, Folder 1-5)
  - 1993 October 3-21 (Box 97, Folder 1-5)
  - 1993 October 22-November 12 (Box 98, Folder 1-5)
  - 1993 November 14-December 6 (Box 99, Folder 1-5)
  - 1993 December 7-1994 January 9 (Box 100, Folder 1-6)
  - 1994 January 10-31 (Box 101, Folder 1-5)
  - 1994 February 1-23 (Box 102, Folder 1-5)
  - 1994 February 24-March17 (Box 103, Folder 1-5)
  - 1994 March 18-April 11 (Box 104, Folder 1-5)
  - 1994 April 12-29 (Box 105, Folder 1-6)
  - 1994 April 29-May 20 (Box 106, Folder 1-5)
  - 1994 May 24-June 15 (Box 107, Folder 1-5)
  - 1994 June 16-July 12 (Box 108, Folder 1-6)
  - 1994 July 13-August 7 (Box 109, Folder 1-6)
  - 1994 August 8-September 5 (Box 110, Folder 1-5)
  - 1994 September 6-26 (Box 111, Folder 1-5)
  - 1994 September 27-October 25 (Box 112, Folder 1-5)
  - 1994 October 25-November 30 (Box 113, Folder 1-5)
  - 1994 December 1-1995 January 6 (Box 114, Folder 1-6)
  - 1995 January 9-February 14 (Box 115, Folder 1-6)
  - 1995 February 15-March 17 (Box 116, Folder 1-5)
  - 1995 March 20-April 18 (Box 117, Folder 1-5)
  - 1995 April 19-May 23 (Box 118, Folder 1-6)